A Guide to the Correspondence and Subject Files of the Virginia Secretary of Education, 1975-1997.
Library of Virginia
- Secretary's correspondence and subject files (Accession 35868), 1994-1997., Extent: 3 cubic feet (3 boxes)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Lord Fairfax Community College, 1997. (Box 1)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Mary Washington College, 1994-1997. (Box 1)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Norfolk State University, 1994-1997. (Box 1)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Northern Virginia Community College, 1997. (Box 1)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Old Dominion University, 1995-1997. (Box 1)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Old Dominion University - Teletechnet, 1995. (Box 1)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Radford University, 1995-1997. (Box 1)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Richard Bland College, 1995-1996. (Box 1)
  - Higher Education Institutions: University of Virginia, 1994-1997. (Box 2)
  - Higher Education Institutions: University of Virginia - Hospital, 1995-1997. (Box 2)
  - Higher Education Institutions: University of Virginia - Health Care Professionals, 1994-1995. (Box 2)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Virginia Commonwealth University, 1995-1997. (Box 2)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Virginia Community College System, 1996-1997. (Box 2)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Virginia Highlands Community College, 1996-1997. (Box 2)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Virginia Insitute of Marine Science, 1995-1997. (Box 2)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Virginia Military Institute, 1997. (Box 2)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Virginia State University, 1995-1997. (Box 2)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Virginia Tech, 1996-1997. (Box 2)
  - Higher Education Institutions: William and Mary, College of, 1996-1997. (Box 2)
  - Higher Education Institutions: Wytheville Community College, 1997. (Box 2)
  - Individuals with Disabilities Act (IDEA), 1994-1997. (Box 2)
  - Standards of Accreditation, 1994-1997. (Box 2)
  - Standards of Learning, 1994-1997. (Box 2)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Academic Standards Testing Committee - Accreditation and Accountability Subcommittee, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Academic Standards Testing Committee - English Beginning Reading Instruction Study, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Academic Standards Testing Committee - Language Arts (Phyllis Coutler), 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Academic Standards Testing Committee - Members memos, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Academic Standards Testing Committee - Minutes and correspondence, 1994. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Academic Standards Testing Committee - Progress Report, 1994 Sept 16. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Academic Standards Testing Committee - Questionnaire, 1995. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Academic Standards Testing Committee - SAT Scores, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Academic Standards Testing Committee - School Report Cards Subcommittee Meeting, 1995 July 26. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Academic Standards Testing Committee - School Report Cards Subcommittee, Research / Journal articles, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Academic Standards Testing Committee - Textbook approval, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Academic Standards Testing Committee - Virginia State Assessment Program, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Academic Standards Testing Committee - Vision Statement and Guidelines for Language Arts and Social Studies, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Advisory Board on Teacher Education and Licensure, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Alternative Routes to Licensure, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Charter Schools - Federal Charter School Program, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Charter Schools - Legislative, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Charter Schools - Review of State Regulations, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Charter Schools - Testimony, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Charter Schools - Virginia School Board Association, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Civil Liability Immunity for Teachers, Talking Points, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Commission meeting, Opening remarks, 1994 Sept 27. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Commission Member list, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Correspondence, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Criminal Background Checks, Report, 1994. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Curriculum Committee, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Educational Alternatives Committee, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Executive Committee Members list, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Executive Orders, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Family Life Education, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: File Organization, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Funding Committee - Meeting and general correspondence, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Funding Committee - Progress Report, 1994 Sept 16. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Goals 2000 - America 2000 v. Goals 2000, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Goals 2000 - Educate Virginia Act, 1994. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Governor's Initiative, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Governor's School, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Governor's Speech, 1994 May 24. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Guidance Counseling - Definitions and Programs, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Guidance Counseling - Legislation (SB 1074), 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Interim Report, 1997 Nov. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Mandates, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: NCATE, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Outcome Accountability Project (OAP) - Report, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Parental and Community Involvement Committee - Minutes, correspondence and reports, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Parental and Community Involvement Committee - Site / School Based Management, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Parental Rights Amendment, 1994. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Press Release, 1994 May 24. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Professional Standards Committee - Minutes, correspondence andf reports, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Progress Reports of the Commission, 1994 Sept 16. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Public Hearings - Southwest, 1994 Oct 11. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Public Hearings - Shenandoah, 1994 Oct 17. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Public Hearings - Tidewater, 1994 Oct 24. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Public Hearings - Roanoke, 1994 Nov 2. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: School Administration, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: School Safety and Discipline Committee - Clippings, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: School Safety and Discipline Committee - Minutes, correspondence and reports, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: School Site Visits, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Special Education, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Standards of Learning - Assessment Update, 1995 Nov 16. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Standards of Quality, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Student Achievement, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Student Support Services and Transition to Work Committee, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Talking Points - Beverly Sgro, 1995 June 9. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Teacher Education - Response to HJR 629, 1995 Nov. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Teacher Tenure / Continuing Contract, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Time - Relationship between staffing and achievement, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Variable / Initiatives - Grading Public Schools, 1994 May 24. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Commission on Champion Schools: Workforce Development Act, 1994-1997. (Box 3)
- Secretary's correspondence and subject files (Accession 36184), 1977-XX., Extent: XX cubic feet (x boxes)
  - Presidential salaries, 1977. (Box 1)
  - Presidential salaries, 1978. (Box 1)
  - Presidential salaries, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Funding Plan (70/30), 1978-1979. (Box 1)
  - Faculty salaries, 1977-1979. (Box 1)
  - Council of Presidents, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Council of Visitors, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Virginia State Library, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Science Museum of Virginia, 1979. (Box 1)
  - State Education Assistance Authority, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Virginia Education Loan Authority, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Christopher Newport College, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Clinch Valley College, 1979. (Box 1)
  - George Mason University, 1979. (Box 1)
  - George Mason University - International Law School, 1979. (Box 1)
  - James Madison University, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Longwood College, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Longwood College - Study, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Mary Washington College, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Norfolk State University, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Old Dominion University, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Radford University, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Richard Bland College, 1979. (Box 1)
  - University of Virginia, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Virginia Associated Research Campus, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Medical College of Virginia, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University / Virginia Community College System Computer Center, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Military Institute, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia State University, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Truck and Ornamentals Research Station, 1979. (Box 2)
  - College of William and Mary, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Institute of Marine Science, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind - Staunton, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind - Hampton, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Schools for the Deaf and Blind - Board, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Advisory Council for Educational Computing, 1979. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Plan for Higher Education, 1979. (Box 3)
  - Management Systems and Development, 1979. (Box 3)
  - Personnel and Training, Dept. of, 1979. (Box 3)
  - Identification and Diagnosis of Children who are Handicapped, 1979. (Box 3)
  - Advertising, 1979. (Box 3)
  - Advisory Research Committee (School Building Specifications), 1979. (Box 3)
  - Agreements - Interagency, 1978. (Box 3)
  - American Association of Community and Junior Colleges - Lifelong Learning, 1979. (Box 3)
- Secretary's correspondence and subject files (Accession 37781), 1980-1983., Extent: 5 cubic feet (5 boxes)
  - Report: Annual Report - Comprehensive Assessment of the Virginia Plan - Council of Higher Education (v. I), 1980. (Box 1)
  - Report: Narrative Assessment - Institutional Reports (Four Year Institutions and Richard Bland College), 1980. (Box 1)
  - Report: Virginia Community College System - Employment Assessment, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Report: Virginia Community College System - Narrative Assessment - Institutional Reports (v. III - Two Year Institutions), 1980. (Box 1)
  - Report: Virginia Community College System - Analysis of Classified Work Force, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Report: Two Year Institutions - Fall Enrollment (v. II-J), 1982. (Box 1)
  - Report: Four Year Institutions - Degrees Confirmed (v. II-D), 1982. (Box 2)
  - Report: Four Year Institutions - Fall Enrollement (v. II-E), 1982. (Box 2)
  - Report: Supplement Earned Degrees and Supplement Fall Enrollement (Four Year Institutions, v. II-F), 1982. (Box 2)
  - Report: Four Year Institutions - Financial Assistance (v. II-G), 1982. (Box 2)
  - Report: Four Year Institutions - Applications, Acceptances and Actual Enrollment; Progression of Students; Reasons for Students Not Returning (v. II-H), 1982. (Box 2)
  - Report: Two Year Institutions - Degrees Confirmed (v. II-I), 1982. (Box 2)
  - Report: Two Year Institutions - Application Acceptances and Actual Enrollments (v. II-K), 1982. (Box 2)
  - Report: Two Year Institutions - Financial Assistance (v. II-L), 1982. (Box 2)
  - Program Proposals: Chrysler Museum, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Program Proposals: Commission for the Arts, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Program Proposals: Council of Higher Education, 1983. (Box 4)
  - Program Proposals: Dept. of Education, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Program Proposals: Dept. of Education - LEA, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Program Proposals: Dept. of Education - SEA, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Program Proposals: Dept. of Education - Summary, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Program Proposals: Eastern Virginia Medical Authority, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Program Proposals: Science Museum of Virginia, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Program Proposals: State Education Assistance Authority, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Program Proposals: Virginia Community College System, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Program Proposals: Virginia Energy Office - Outer Continental Shelf, 1979. (Box 4)
  - Program Proposals: Virginia Military Institute, 1983. (Box 4)
  - Program Proposals: Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Program Proposals: Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind - Hampton, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Program Proposals: Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind - Staunton, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Program Proposals: Virginia State Library, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Program Proposals: Virginia Tech, 1983. (Box 4)
  - Program Proposals: Virginia Truck and Ornamentals Research Station, 1983. (Box 3)
  - Economic Development Projects: Correspondence of the Secretary, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Center for Innovative Technology, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Commonwealth Televised Graduate Engineering Programs, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Eastern Virginia Medical Authority, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Education, Dept. of - Governor's Magnate School for Experimental Programs in Science and Technlogy, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Education, Dept. of - Governor's Magnate School for Fine Arts, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Education, Dept. of - Mobile Technology Training, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Education, Dept. of - Residential School for the Gifted and Talented, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Education, Dept. of - Science Education Enhancements, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Education, Dept. of - Governor's School for Educational Research and Technology, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Science Museum of Virginia, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Science Museum of Virginia - Museum Project, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Southeastern Universities Research Association (SURA), 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Southeastern Universities Research Association (SURA) - National Electron Accelerator Laboratory, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: State Council of Higher Education for Virginia - Commonwealth Televised Graduate Engineering Programs, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: State Council of Higher Education for Virginia - Eminent Scholars, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: State Council of Higher Education for Virginia - Marine Science Consortium, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Virginia Museum of Fine Arts - Statewide Outreach Art Mobile, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Virginia Museum of Fine Arts - Video Programs on Art, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Virginia Peninsula Vocational Technical Center, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Virginia State Library - Statewide Library Network, 1983. (Box 5)
  - Economic Development Projects: Virginia Truck and Ornamentals Station, 1983. (Box 5)